<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Super Massive Black Holes on Yunliang Zheng&#39;s Homepage</title>
        <link>https://al-yl.github.io/tags/super-massive-black-holes/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Super Massive Black Holes on Yunliang Zheng&#39;s Homepage</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>zh-CN</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 10:37:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://al-yl.github.io/tags/super-massive-black-holes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Literature Reading Notes: Little Red Dots (2025 Vol.15)</title>
        <link>https://al-yl.github.io/posts/note2515/lrd/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 10:37:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://al-yl.github.io/posts/note2515/lrd/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://al-yl.github.io/posts/note2515/AGN-Torus.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Literature Reading Notes: Little Red Dots (2025 Vol.15)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since 2023, a large number of images captured by the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) have continuously revealed a surprising phenomenon: in the first few hundred million years after the birth of the first galaxies, there existed numerous mysterious objects known as &amp;ldquo;Little Red Dots.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img 
    src=&#34;https://al-yl.github.io/posts/note2515/LRD.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;LRD&#34; 
    width=&#34;100%&#34;
    
  &gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    False-color stamps of 20 little red dots from &lt;a href=&#39;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2306.05448&#39;&gt;Matthee et al. (2023)&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the image, these objects indeed appear as individual “little red dots.” However, it is important to note that the JWST captures images in the infrared band. The “little red dots” we see are mostly “false-color” images created by combining monochromatic images from three bands above 2.5 microns, with blue, green, and red assigned to short, medium, and long wavelengths, respectively, to produce the composite color image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we use JWST’s short-wavelength infrared bands, such as 1.15 microns (F115W), 1.5 microns (F150W), and 2 microns (F200W), and assign colors from short to long wavelength as blue/green/red, these “little red dots” would actually appear as “little blue dots.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to emphasize, though, that the infrared radiation we see from them actually originates in their ultraviolet and optical emissions. Their high redshifts are what shift this light into the infrared bands for our observation. In fact, the spectra of these little red dots generally exhibit a V-shaped profile, as if two radiation components dominate: one in the ultraviolet, and the other in the infrared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img 
    src=&#34;https://al-yl.github.io/posts/note2515/Kokorev&amp;#43;2401.09981.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;LRD&#34; 
    width=&#34;70%&#34;
    
  &gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    From &lt;a href=&#39;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2401.09981&#39;&gt;Kokorev et al. (2024)&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to subsequent observational evidence, these “Little Red Dots” (LRDs) are in fact accreting supermassive black holes (SMBHs) at the centers of galaxies. In fact, nearly every galaxy hosts a SMBH at its center. Take our own Milky Way, for example: the central SMBH has 4.3 million solar mass, while the stellar mass is about 52 billion solar masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SMBHs at the centers of galaxies usually grow together with their host galaxies. For instance, when two galaxies merge, the black holes at their centers will eventually coalesce into a larger one. Thus, from an overall trend, the closer we look to the present day (i.e., later cosmic times), the more massive black holes tend to be. This indicates that black hole growth is a gradual, cumulative process. At least before the launch of the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST), it was widely believed that this growth in mass should be relatively slow, requiring billions of years of cosmic evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-evidence-from-jwst&#34;&gt;New evidence from JWST&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, these LRDs turn out to be far too massive: as early as when the Universe was less than 500 million years old, some SMBHs had already reached few tens million to even a hundred million solar masses, and these are not isolated cases; even more strikingly, the stellar mass of their host galaxies just over a billion solar masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that at such an early stage of the Universe, not a very few galaxies had already grown to enough massive to challenge current theories of galaxy formation, yet the growth rate of their central SMBHs appears to be even more extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img 
    src=&#34;https://al-yl.github.io/posts/note2515/Maiolino&amp;#43;2305.12492.png&#34; 
    alt=&#34;LRD&#34; 
    width=&#34;80%&#34;
    
  &gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The relative ratio of SMBH mass to stellar mass in many high redshift galaxies is exceedingly large compared with that in the local Universe. From &lt;a href=&#39;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2305.12492&#39;&gt;Maiolino et al. (2023)&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aizrg1CA5DE&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
