<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Galaxy Groups on Yunliang Zheng&#39;s Homepage</title>
        <link>https://al-yl.github.io/categories/galaxy-groups/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Galaxy Groups on Yunliang Zheng&#39;s Homepage</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>zh-CN</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 21:40:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://al-yl.github.io/categories/galaxy-groups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Compact Groups of Galaxies in SDSS, GAMA, and LAMOST</title>
        <link>https://al-yl.github.io/posts/first/firstpaper/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 21:40:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://al-yl.github.io/posts/first/firstpaper/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-compact-groups-of-galaxies-&#34;&gt;What is Compact Groups of Galaxies ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, a compact group of galaxies (&lt;strong&gt;CG&lt;/strong&gt;, hereafter) is a kind of special galaxy system where the galaxy members are separated at distances &lt;strong&gt;of the order of galaxy size&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://al-yl.github.io/posts/first/QuiJWST.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above image shows a very typical CG, Stephan’s Quintet, which is photoed by James Webb Space Telescope. Although we call it a “Quintet&amp;quot;, only four of them on the right side of the image are truly close together. The leftmost one, called NGC 7320, is well in the foreground compared with the other four galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In CGs, galaxy members frequently interact each other and are expected to form a single elliptical galaxy within a short period. The high density and low velocity dispersion make CG an ideal laboratory for studying galaxy interaction and the merging process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-catalogs-of-compact-groups-of-galaxies&#34;&gt;The Catalogs of Compact Groups of Galaxies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To study the properties of CGs, we select CGs in the Main Galaxy Sample of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). The SDSS Main Galaxy Sample (&lt;strong&gt;SDSS DR14 Version&lt;/strong&gt;) contains $\sim 700,000$ nearby galaxies with redshift $z \le 0.2$ and $r$-band magnitude of $14.00 \le r \le 17.77$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sdss.org/dr16/algorithms/legacy_tiling/#FiberCollisions&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Fiber Collision Effect&lt;/a&gt;, not all of the galaxies have spectroscopic redshift, especially for the galaxies live in a higher number density region. The search for CGs is severely hindered by such effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reduce the incompleteness as much as possible, we take the complementary redshift measurements from GAMA and LAMOST datasets. The incompleteness has been reduced from $\sim 7$ % to $\sim 5$ %. And we constructed the largest and most complete CG catalogs to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our samples include 6144 CGs with complete redshifts and 8022 CG candidates which might contain interlopers. For the CG candidates, there are three different kinds of of cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://al-yl.github.io/posts/first/Case.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above cartoon shows all of the cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genuine CGs&lt;/strong&gt; with complete spectroscopic redshifts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 1&lt;/strong&gt;: At least one of the members lacks redshift data but the others have genuine spectroscopic redshifts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 2&lt;/strong&gt;: All the members have genuine spectroscopic redshifts but at least one galaxy without redshift lies in the isolation rings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case 3&lt;/strong&gt;: The combination of Cases 1 and 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the example SDSS images of a genuine CG and each case of CG candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://al-yl.github.io/posts/first/CP4.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small white circles locate the group members with spectroscopic redshifts, while the small green circles label the galaxies without redshifts. The red circles represent the foreground or background galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
